someone recently asked me if i have
achieved any of my dreams
and come to think of it i did in a way
but
they also failed me i reached some of my
goals but those achievements didn't give
me what i was looking for
i wanted general happiness of course and
courage
self-worth and satisfaction in my way of
living
slowly quietly
following the pace of the seasons
i still stop and wonder sometimes if i'm
missing out on something big living this
way
and i think that's a common feeling no
matter what life we choose
since it was such a rainy day and there
were not so many hikers and other
foragers out because of the weather i
decided that i would go out and collect
some yarrow because i have some new
recipes that i've been wanting to try
with the arrow and depending on where
you live you may see them all over the
place they look like this they're these
tiny little white flowers
and they are incredibly healing and have
an amazing history anyway i have gone to
the little forest area right behind my
home and so we'll see what we find and
i'm excited to take you with me
[Music]
so i have successfully found a basket
full
and so we're gonna take them home dry
them
and
experiment a little bit
so
[Music]
a surprising amount of people purchase
homes in this area only to move away the
next year saying that it was too quiet
the winter's too cold not enough social
gatherings and opportunities
all of these are valid and much like the
old folk tale of the city and country
mouse i know that this is where i truly
belong and feel most fulfilled
though it isn't a lifestyle meant for
everyone
even though sometimes i still do doubt
my path
i know that i can always find answers in
nature
for example yarrow is a plant with a
rich history and yet is considered by
most to be a troublesome weed it is an
interesting metaphor for finding
fulfillment in life as a quiet and
sensitive person
we may sometimes wish we are louder and
brighter a gorgeous luscious rose
instead of a diminutive weed
i think we all have those insecure
moments where we wish we felt more brave
and notable
but perhaps we're forgetting that like
gyro you can't know much about a plant
simply by looking at it
their strength lies within in something
deeper something others may not always
notice
i take great wisdom from this flower
remembering that we should never
question our worth instead we need to
recognize it and not compare value with
others
we just need to grow and offer healing
to those who come in contact much like
the simple wild gyro
when i started the journey of healing my
body and mind after many years of
self-harm i realized that it had to
begin with opening that little corner of
my heart that felt somehow i deserved to
be mistreated every time a past bully
had called me names or hurt me i thought
for some reason it was no more than i
deserved that was the fundamental shift
that had to happen the belief that i am
worthy and good and you
you are also worthy and good
because it begins with believing we're
good enough to get help to love to begin
from wherever we are mistakes and
shortcomings and go forth on that
journey of who we will become
and that person doesn't need to achieve
anything to be extraordinary
so yes perhaps my dreams failed me in a
way distracting me with the false
promise that success or reaching your
worldly goals will make you value
yourself by default
so now i wake up each morning and
rewrite the story
paula isn't living in order to achieve
great things she doesn't need to prove
herself
instead she's here to simply be and
through that process she will find her
greatness and her voice and her
self-love
and so i hope will you
[Music]
do
as i am sitting here enjoying my tea and
shortbread and a good book
i realized that it has been quite a
while since i really took time to enjoy
a moment like this i've been quite
caught up with work but also in the
process of continuing to move into the
house and try to get
some plants planted and just get a lot
of things done it's a wonderful reminder
of how important it is to take those
steps to take care of yourself so that
you can better take care of others and
be more authentic and giving in that way
and have more of that
energy and vibrance and zest for life
that i think only comes when you are
well fed and well rested and at peace
with yourself and really taking those
moments to take care
of your
you know physical mental and spiritual
life at least in my case one thing that
i did recently was i found these little
transparent
decals that i put in the windows in
order to keep the birds from flying at
the windows because i was very concerned
about the risk of any little bird losing
his life by um hitting the window panes
and so i put them in the windows and
they look absolutely darling so i'll put
in some clips of how they look but
that's just a fun idea for you in case
you've ever wanted to decorate your
windows but that being said i think i'm
going to go out and garden a little bit
i highly encourage you to try yarrow
lemonade if you have yarrow growing in
your area it is a really fun recipe and
i think whenever i work with flowers i'm
always fascinated by the interesting
flavors you get from them because yarrow
is normally a very bitter plant but when
made into euro syrup and combined with
lemon it creates a really interesting
and lovely taste in my opinion but as
always it is not for everyone anyway i
hope you have a wonderful day and i'm
sending you all my love thank you for
everyone who pre-ordered my book i
really deeply appreciate it it has been
so exciting to finally have something
available that i've been working on for
gosh i think
a year now
so it is available worldwide i will
leave links down below
and um thank you everyone thank you so
much thank you all so much i'm sending
you all my love and i will see you very
very soon
goodbye
you